northstandchat.com 2019-03-30

# North Stand Chat - Privacy Policy

￼ 

## Your Privacy and North Stand Chat

1\. Introduction.  
This Privacy Notice is to help you understand the types of personal data we may collect about you when you interact with us and the ways in which we use this information.

2\. Who are we?  
North Stand Chat is owned and managed by Blue Seagull Technology Limited, which is the controller of the personal data processed on this website as detailed in this Privacy Policy. You can contact us in writing c/o One 2 One Accountants, Monarch House, 1-7 Smyth Road, Bristol, BS3 2BX.

3\. What types of lawful basis may we rely on to collect and use your personal data?  
The law on data protection sets out different reasons for which a company may collect and process your personal data. We rely on the following:

Consent  
In specific situations, we can process your data with your consent.

For example, if you select to register with North Stand Chat.

Contract  
We have the right to process your personal data if it is necessary to fulfil a contract we have with you, or when we are taking steps to enter into a contract with you at your request.

For example, if you wish to advertise your business on North Stand Chat.

Legitimate interest  
We may use your data to pursue our legitimate business interests, or the legitimate interests of a third party in a way which might reasonably be expected as part of running our business and is not overridden by your rights.

For example, the personal data requested during registration is necessary to participate on our public discussion forum.

Legal obligation  
If it is a requirement of law enforcement or other legal obligation, we may need to collect and process your personal data.

For example, we can pass on details of people involved in criminal activity affecting North Stand Chat.

4\. When do we collect your personal data?  
When you register to be a member of North Stand Chat.  
When you engage with North Stand Chat as a member.  
When you contact us by any means with queries, complaints, etc.

5\. What type of personal data do we collect and why do we collect it?  
In order to provide North Stand Chat:  
We collect your chosen username - This is the name chosen by you at the time of registration on the site. We use this to allow you to make posts and interact with the site.

We collect your email address - We use this to confirm your registration, to allow you to make changes to your account, reset your password and to send you notifications that you have consented to.

We collect your date of birth - We collect this at time of registration and we use it to verify that you are aged 16 or over, a requirement to use our site. We also use your date of birth to help recover lost account details if you forget them.   
We collect your IP address - We collect your IP address at time of registration and every time you make a post on the forums for security against unauthorised access and abuse.

For security we will also keep an encrypted record of your password. We cannot read/decode/decipher that password. If you forget your password it can only be reset by generating a new password.

6\. How do we use your personal data?  
We use the information entered at registration to identify our members and to provide, maintain and improve this publicly accessible discussion forum service.

To protect our business and your accounts from illegal activities.  
To comply with legal requirements.  
We store and process the data under the legitimate interests of both you as the registered member and Blue Seagull Technology Limited in order to provide the public discussion forum you have requested to be registered and make posts on. 

7\. How long do we store your personal data for?  
The personal data you enter at registration is stored all the time you are a member of North Stand Chat. If you have not logged in to North Stand Chat for a period of 5 years, your account registration data will be removed. 

8\. Do we share personal data?

We do not sell your personal data to any third parties.  
We do not share your personal data with third parties except for in very specific circumstances. For example: We may pass on required details to the appropriate authorities in any abuse or fraud investigation. Or if we believe in good faith that disclosure is required by law.  
We may give limited access to an IT company if necessary in support of our server management.  
Page viewing data may be collected by Google via cookies (see section 17).  
If the website should be sold to new owners, your personal data may be transferred to the new owners providing that the data is used substantially in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

9\. What are your rights regarding the processing of your personal data?  
A summary of your different rights:

The right to object to processing of your personal data in certain circumstances.

For example, you have an absolute right to stop your data being used for direct marketing.

The right to restrict processing of your personal data in certain circumstances.

For example, you wish the data to be hidden but need it to remain to exercise or defend a legal claim.

The right to withdraw consent.

For example, you can turn off email notifications from the forum in your User Control Panel at any time.

The right to access to the personal data we hold about you, free of charge in most cases.

Please contact us if you wish to have a copy of your personal data we hold. It may take some time to compile this data and download.

The right to the correction of your personal data when incorrect, out of date or incomplete.

The accuracy of your personal data is important. To access your personal data please login to your North Stand Chat User Control Panel and you can view and update your details as needed. Please pay attention to your registered email address and update it if you change your email provider. The only way you can reset a forgotten password is via this email address.

The right to be forgotten.  
You have the right to be removed from this site. Please contact us if you wish to exercise this right. You must be logged into North Stand Chat in order for us to positively identify you. When we receive your request and validate your identity, we will remove the personal data that we hold about you within 30 days and it will no longer be processed.

Your posts made on North Stand Chat will remain with the username anonymised. This is to retain the integrity and structure of the discussion forums. You will be able to remove any specific posts that you no longer wish to display before you ask for your account to be deleted. See section 12.

The right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.  
See section 18 for contact details.

10\. How do we handle children's privacy?  
To register on the DIBB you must be at least 16 years of age. We therefore do not knowingly process data for children. However, please note that this is a public forum and can therefore be viewed by all ages.

11\. Does our privacy policy apply to external links?  
Our website and forum posts by members may contain links to other websites. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

12\. How do we handle personal messages (PM's) on our forums?  
Personal messages sent via North Stand Chat are stored in our database. A limited number of personnel have access to this database and it is possible that your messages could be read by those personnel. North Stand Chat administrators do not routinely read personal messages, but it may become necessary to do sowhen abuse has been reported or suspected. The database will from time to time be scanned for key words and phrases that break our terms of service. With that in mind, North Stand Chat recommend that you do not use our PM system to transmit personal messages that you do not want anyone else to access.

13\. How do we handle any personal data in posts on the DIBB public forum?  
Due to the real-time nature of North Stand Chat, it is impossible for North Stand Chat staff to review messages or confirm the validity of information posted.

If you provide personal information in a post, that personal information will be publicly posted and otherwise disclosed without limitation as to its use by us or by a third party.

You are in control of your own posts and can edit and delete the posts you make in an open thread at any time. If the thread is locked, you will need to report your own post and ask admin to delete it for you.

14\. How do we secure data?  
We take steps to ensure your personal data is treated securely. 

We regularly review our security procedures to consider appropriate new technology and methods. Please be aware that, despite our best efforts, no security measures are perfect or impenetrable.

Any password you enter is also stored in an encrypted form. We cannot read/decode/decipher that password. If you forget your password, it can only be reset by generating a new password.

15\. Do we use automated decision making?  
Our software checks the registration IP address to make sure it has not previously been used to post forum spam. New registrations will then be manually checked by a member of staff before approval.

16\. What are cookies?  
A cookie is a small text file, which a website stores on your computer's hard drive (if your Web browser permits). They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site.

Cookies are used by websites to save user preferences between visits.

Types of cookies:

Category 1 - Strictly necessary cookies  
These cookies are essential to using the website. Without these cookies services you have asked for cannot be provided and the website will not function.

Category 2 - Performance cookies  
These cookies are used for Web analytics, Ad response rates and Affiliate tracking. These cookies collect information about how visitors use a website, for instance which pages visitors go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages. These cookies don't collect information that identifies a visitor. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. It is only used to improve how a website works.

Category 3 - Functionality cookies  
These cookies are used for things such as remembering settings a user has applied to a website such as layout, font size, preferences, colours etc. The information these cookies collect may be anonymised and they cannot track your browsing activity on other websites.

Category 4 - Targeting or advertising cookies  
Cookies placed by advertising networks to collect browsing habits in order to target relevant adverts to the user.

Session cookies expire when you close your browser. Persistent cookies have a lifetime set by the website and will retain information that can be used when you reopen a website in the future.

First Party Cookies are set by the website you are actually visiting. Third Party Cookies are set from content displayed on the website from other websites. This can be from advertising or sharing tools such as Facebook, YouTube or Twitter.

17\. What cookies does North Stand Chat use?

First Party Cookies used on this website:  
Cookie Name Cat Type Lifetime Description PHPSESSID 1 Session --- Used for Website Operation bbsessionhash 1 Session --- Used for Forum Operation bbthread_lastview 3 Session --- Used for Forum Operation bbforum_view 3 Session --- Used for Forum Operation editor_height 3 Session --- Used for Forum Operation skimlinks_enabled 3 Session --- Used for Forum Operation bblastactivity 3 Persistent 365 Days Used for Forum Operation bblastvisit 3 Persistent 365 Days Used for Forum Operation bbpassword 3 Persistent 365 Days Used for Forum Operation bbuserid 3 Persistent 365 Days Used for Forum Operation vbulletin_collapse 3 Persistent 365 Days Used for Forum Operation cookieConsent 3 Persistent 365 Days Directive Notification

Third party cookies  
Viewing embedded media such as a YouTube video in a post may set a cookie from the vendor to track views. We also supply advertising for 3rd parties and these 3rd parties may store a cookie on your browsing device. Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to this website. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to you based on your visit to this site and other sites on the Internet.

Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the advertising opt-out page. (Alternatively, users can opt out of a third-party vendor's use of cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page).

Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit: allaboutcookies.org.

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit: tools.google.com.

18\. Contacting the Regulator  
If you feel that your personal data has not been handled correctly, or you are unhappy with our response to any requests you have made to us regarding the use of your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner's Office.

You can contact them by calling 0303 123 1113. Or go online to ico.org.uk/concerns.

If you are based outside the UK, you have the right to lodge your complaint with the relevant data protection regulator in your country of residence.

19\. Updating this Privacy Policy  
Please note this Privacy Policy may be updated or amended at any time, in order for example to:

Comply with any further legal requirements.  
To enable us to use personal data for a new purpose with the aim of improving your experience on this site, or to meet our changing business needs.  
Members may be advised of significant changes of the Privacy Policy updates via email so please ensure your email address is kept updated on this website. In addition, we suggest you refer back to our Privacy Policy on a regular basis, to read any updates and as a reminder of the personal data we collect and your rights regarding your personal data.

Changes to this Privacy Policy become immediately effective upon being posted on this site.  
Last Updated: 24th May 2018
